<bibdata type="standard">
  <fetched>2022-05-29</fetched>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">OGC Testbed-13: 3D Tiles and I3S Interoperability and Performance Engineering Report</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">OGC Testbed-13: 3D Tiles and I3S Interoperability and Performance Engineering Report</title>
  <uri type="obp">http://docs.opengeospatial.org/per/17-046.html</uri>
  <docidentifier type="OGC" primary="true">17-046</docidentifier>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2018-03-05</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="author"/>
    <person>
      <name>
        <completename>Volker Coors</completename>
      </name>
    </person>
  </contributor>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>Open Geospatial Consortium</name>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <language>en</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This OGC Testbed 13 Engineering Report (ER) documents the overall architecture developed in the Interoperability of 3D Tiles and I3S using a 3D Portrayal Service and performance study of 3D tiling algorithms activity. The report also summarizes a proof-of-concept of the use of 3D Tiles and I3S as data delivery formats for the OGC 3D Portrayal Service interface standard. The report captures the results from the interoperability tests performed as part of the 3D Tiles and I3S testbed work package. Specifically, this OGC Testbed activity focused on the following tasks:

CityGML files converted into Cesium 3D Tiles using Analytical Graphics (AGI’s) 3D Tiling Pipeline, and Cesium as the rendering client;

An OGC CDB data store converted into 3D Tiles using Compusult’s Streaming engine, Cesium and Ecere’s GNOSIS as rendering client;

CityGML data store GeoRocket, 3DPS with 3D Tiles as data delivery format, and Cesium as rendering client;

CityGML converted into I3S, 3DPS with I3S as data delivery format, and Cesium as rendering client;

CityGML converted into I3S using ArcGIS and FME, 3DPS with I3S as data delivery format, and rendering in ArcGIS client;

CityGML with application domain extension stored in GeoRocket, converted to 3D Tiles, and Cesium as the rendering client;

3D Tiles (generated by all streaming engines visualized) from Ecere’s GNOSIS rendering client;

CDB visualized directly from Ecere’s GNOSIS rendering client; and

I3S visualized from Ecere’s GNOSIS rendering client.

</abstract>
  <ext>
    <doctype>engineering-report</doctype>
    <editorialgroup>
      <committee>technical</committee>
    </editorialgroup>
  </ext>
</bibdata>